<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PORTFOLIO on Felix Zhang</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PORTFOLIO on Felix Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Felix Zhang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:47:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/sample-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-ordering-platform-br&#34;&gt;Online Ordering Platform &lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Engaged in developing the frontend using &lt;strong&gt;Angular 15&lt;/strong&gt;, utilized latest features including &lt;strong&gt;Standalone Components&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Utilized &lt;strong&gt;Figma&lt;/strong&gt; to design pages including Home, Explore, Rewards and Orders,&#xA;ensuring intuitive and elegant digital experiences.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developed the &amp;ldquo;Explore&amp;rdquo; page, a core feature that allowed users to browse and&#xA;search restaurants, add items to their cart, and proceed to checkout.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Used &lt;strong&gt;RxJS Observables&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HttpClient Service&lt;/strong&gt; to make API calls. Leveraged&#xA;RxJS operators including &lt;strong&gt;debounce&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;switchMap&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the UI remains&#xA;responsive without throttling performance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implemented &lt;strong&gt;infinite scrolling&lt;/strong&gt;, loads more restaurants dynamically as the&#xA;user scrolls down.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Utilized &lt;strong&gt;BehaviorSubject&lt;/strong&gt; to to synchronize the selected items between the&#xA;menu popup and the cart icon in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrated &lt;strong&gt;Stripe&lt;/strong&gt; to implement checkout via multiple payment options&#xA;including credit cards, Apple Pay, and Google Pay.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joined a team to transplant the web app to mobile platforms using &lt;strong&gt;Ionic&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;Adapted components such as &lt;strong&gt;ion-button&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;ion-input&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;ion-modal&lt;/strong&gt; to create&#xA;a native-like feel on mobile devices while maintaining core business logic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Utilized &lt;strong&gt;Capacitor&lt;/strong&gt; to integrate native device features into the mobile version,&#xA;including push notifications and geolocation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Focused on &lt;strong&gt;Web Vitals&lt;/strong&gt;. Implemented &lt;strong&gt;lazy loading&lt;/strong&gt; for non-crucial&#xA;components including cart and checkout to optimize program performance.&#xA;Utilized &lt;strong&gt;OnPush&lt;/strong&gt; change detection strategy to avoid unnecessary rerendering&#xA;of the page, optimizing the performance of the application.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Resolved &lt;strong&gt;cross-browser compatibility issues&lt;/strong&gt;. Utilized &lt;strong&gt;BrowserStack&lt;/strong&gt; for&#xA;extensive testing, and implemented &lt;strong&gt;polyfills&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CSS resets&lt;/strong&gt; to standardize&#xA;behavior across platforms.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Partnered with UI/UX designers to integrate &lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt; into the design&#xA;process. Developed accessible color palettes with sufficient contrast ratios&#xA;to aid users with visual impairments. Utilized &lt;strong&gt;WAVE&lt;/strong&gt; to identify and address&#xA;accessibility issues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Utilized Flexible Layouts, Media Queries, Relative Units and Responsive&#xA;Typography to ensure &lt;strong&gt;Responsive Web Design&lt;/strong&gt;, delivering a seamless user&#xA;experience across various devices and screen sizes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Familiar with &lt;strong&gt;CI/CD&lt;/strong&gt; pipeline using &lt;strong&gt;Jenkins&lt;/strong&gt;. Conducted unit testing using&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Jasmine&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Karma&lt;/strong&gt;, and end-to-end testing using &lt;strong&gt;Cypress&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the&#xA;robustness and reliability of the application.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Participated in &lt;strong&gt;Agile&lt;/strong&gt; processes including sprint planning, daily stand-ups and&#xA;retrospectives. Designed and allocated tickets in &lt;strong&gt;JIRA&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure timely delivery&#xA;of features.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
